

DANIEL UNGUREANU

JUNIOR PYTHON DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

RNP ROMSILVA - ADMINISTRAŢIA PARCULUI NATURAL BUCEGI R.A.

IT SPECIALIST

present

2022 -

Sept.

Dec. 2021 - present

2022

2017

Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2018

2014

May 2012 - Jan.

• GIS database maintenance, digital infrastructure for wireless survey data transmission from the field using QFIELD - cloud - QGIS, developed a new website in django / python / javascript / html with a payment system, graphics for online advertising, local network maintenance.

UNGUREANU WEBTECH SRL

SOFTWARE DEV & ADMINISTRATOR

• Developing online apps for clients using Python/Django, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, AWS, Docker, Asyncio, Linux

OBICEIURI SANATOASE SRL

BUSINESS ASOCIATE

· An artisan bakery i co-founded and managed the online presence.

FUNDATIA CONSERVATION CARPATHIA

PROJECT ASISSTANT MANAGER

· Coordinated field activities, forest inventories, did periodical reports, used QGIS and ARCGIS 10.2 extensively for mapping parcels and for planning management actions, handheld GIS devices

FBR FOREST OPS S.A

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR

· Initialy started as deputy forest engineer on forest survey using QGIS and handheld NAUTIZ devices, then been promoted technical director. planning operations responsible for using QGIS, coordinating team, etc.

PROFILE

My professional story starts with a B.Sc. (2010) & a M.Sc. in Forest Ecology (2012) in Brasov, Romania, with major interest though in computer sciences and statistics. Gathered over 8 years of experience with GIS software (QGIS, ARCGIS, TERRASYNC, QFIELD) applied in nature related projects. In 2018 i started a journey in software development with python and specialized in web development with python and Django, mostly freelancing projects. Also learned, along the way, to work with MYSQL and POSTGRESQL databases, HTML, JavaScript, Git, a bit of docker, pandas, matplotlib, numpy, asynchronous programming, AWS, payment gateways, Linux, Ubuntu servers. My aim for the future is to get involved in challenging software development projects and acquire new skills.

EDUCATION

INITIATION INTO PROGRAMMING

SCRIU COD

2018

2017 -

2012

2010 -

2006 - 2010

www.scriucod.eu

• A 6 months python programming course, where we would learn from actually working on small personal projects, that each of us was free to choose.

MASTER IN SCIENCE

UNIVERSITATEA TRANSILVANIA www.unitbv.ro

• Built or Improved skills on forest ecology, surveys, habitats classification, forest site conditions, GIS software, relational databases, research, statistical analysis with R & Statistica

BACHELOR DIPLOMA - FOREST ENGINEER

UNIVERSITATEA TRANSILVANIA

• Built skills on forest management, ecology, wildlife, site index, statistical analysis, ArcGIS & QGIS, R, monitoring, research

SKILLS

Python Django Data Science JavaScript

Web development SQL databases

Pandas

QGIS

Linux

Networks

ArcGIS

Ecology

Project Management Digital graphics

LANGUAGES

English German

2011

Aug.

Apr. 2011 - lun. 2011

Sept. 2009 - Mar. 2010

2015

Apr.

EXCHANGE PROGRAMS

PART OF A LIFE+ PROJECT

ARGENTINA & CHILE Apr. 2015

• A 3 weeks visit in National Parks and protected areas created by Tompkins Conservation in Argentina and Chile.

CANADA

visiting field work sites in forestry and protected areas.

ERASMUS MUNDUS SCHOLARSHIP

GEORG-AUGUST-UNIVERSITÄT GÖTTINGEN

lab and practicing statistics in R.

ERASMUS MUNDUS SCHOLARSHIP

GÖTTINGEN

Georg - August Universität Göttingen. It consisted of courses on international forest practices, plus German language courses.

GREECE

A 3 weeks visit at Aristotle University in Thessaloniki for practicing data cluster analysis on plant species and site conditions.

CERTIFICATES

Top 25% Python Certificate

TESTDOME

Aprilie 2022

anuarie 2021

anuarie 2021

2021

Oct

Popular test for Python skills

Data Analysis with Python

FREECODECAMP

• Data Analysis test using Python programming language, along with some of its statistics modules: Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy. The test certifies solving difficult problems and a total of 300 hours of applied work.

Scientific Computing with Python

FREECODECAMP

• Scientific Data Analysis test using Python programming language, along with its statistics and data science modules: Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy. The test certifies solving difficult problems and a total of 300 hours of applied work.

International English Language Testing System

BRITISH COUNCIL BUCHAREST

The result was Band 8, meaning a C1 level - Fluent speaker, by EU standards.

OCEAN PROGRAM BETWEEN E.U. SI **ALBERTA & BRITISH COLUMBIA**

A 3 weeks excursion in western Canada,

• A 3 months exchange program at Georg - August Universität Göttingen, doing research work in an entomology

GEORG-AUGUST-UNIVERSITÄT

• An exchange program lasting 6 months

SUMMER SCHOOL